# SAZZAD HOSSAIN

## Manager

unitaria 🔘 shazzadhossain504@gmail.com 🕜 linkedin.com/in/shazzad-hossain-a55284227

Dhaka, Bangladesh



## **SUMMARY**

I am a dedicated and driven professional with a focus on achieving success through diligence and determination. I possess a strong educational background in Executive-MBA and Computer Science, coupled with valuable experience in material management and accounting. My passion for photography, sports, and engaging in community projects complements my professional skills, allowing me to contribute effectively in any team setting.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Executive-MBA

University of Dhaka

**=** 01/2024 - 01/1970 Ohaka

#### B.Sc

**American International** University-Bangladesh GPA 3.44 / 4.0

## LANGUAGES

Bangla Native • **English** Proficient ●●●

#### **PASSIONS**



#### Hobbies and Interests

Photography and travelling showcase my creativity, while sports and community involvement keep me physically active and engaged.



## Chess

A strategic mind for chess allows me to enhance my analytical skills and problem-solving abilities.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Managerial Accounting

## Baybreeze Company LTD

A dealership company which operates with Pepsi.

- Making critical decisions, observe route and sells and taking actions accordingly
- Handled accounting sector and maintain a seller
- Minimized inventory loss.

## Telesales Specialist

#### SkyTech Solutions

**iii** 01/2022 - 10/2022 Ohaka, Bangladesh selling cleaning products

- Maintained proficiency in sales techniques to achieve revenue goals
- Helped new telemarketers to learn best practice, communication strategies and performance standards

## Material Controller

#### Shinbo C. Limited

**#** 02/2023 - 05/2023 O Dhaka

A company involved in project management for the third terminal of Hazrat Shahjalal International

- Organized and maintained files of project documentation
- Supported in gathering teams keeping records of the works and maintained engineering specifications
- Managed a medium number of groups to distribute and maintain materials for the third terminal of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport

## Event-Tourism & peace

## University of Dhaka

**m** 09/2024 - 09/2024 Ohaka

Organized event focusing on Tourism and Peace.

- Managed administrative logistics of event planning including fees collection, event booking and event promotions.
- Supported the Coordinator (prof. Dr. Kamrul Hassan) by developing status reports related to planning, scheduling, resourcing and proposal development.
- Prepared speech for students and myself as well.

## **SKILLS**

Github **Autocad** E-Learning Java Latex **MySQL PHP Proteus Terminal Event Management** 

#### **PROJECTS**

## News Portal Management System

A project aimed at creating an efficient news management

Developed a news portal management system to streamline news delivery and management processes.

## **Busy Street**

**a** 01/1970 - 01/1970 Remote A project designed to promote local businesses through an online platform.

Built Busy Street, a platform showcasing various businesses and offerings in urban areas.

## Learning through E-Learning in Pandemic

Thesis project examining the impact of E-Learning during the pandemic.

Conducted research and developed a thesis on learning through E-Learning during the pandemic.